Guide to the Douglas C. Engelbart Papers M0638
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Douglas C. Engelbart papers
1953-1998
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
M0638
383 Linear Feet
This collection documents that activities of Douglas C. Engelbart, a computer scientist whose pioneering work in the 1950s and 1960s (first at SRI International, later at Tymshare, Inc.) led to the development of the interactive personal computer. Most of the publications in this collection were produced while Engelbart was at SRI. Includes professional papers, correspondence, research proposals, technical reports, notes, journals, and computer disks, as well as audiovisual meterial on a variety of media.
Acronyms & Abbreviations
AKW (Augmented Knowledge Workshop) ARC (Augmented Research Center) BC (Bootstrap Community) BS (Bootstrap) CML (Command Meta Language) CSCW (Computer Supported Co-operative Work) DCE (Douglas C. Engelbart) DEC (Digital Equipment Corp.) McAir (McDonnell Douglas Airforce Base) NIC (National Information Center) NL (oNLine System) NP (needs & possibilities) RINS (Research Intelligence System) SRI (Stanford Research Institute) TD (to digest) TM (Text Manipulation)
Acquisition Information
This collection given by Douglas Engelbart to Stanford University, Special Collections from 1986-2007.
Conditions Governing Access
No restrictions.
Scope and Content
Professional papers, including correspondence, research proposals, technical reports, notes, journals, and computer disks, as well as audiovisual material on a variety of media.
Biography
Born January 30, 1925. In the late 1940s, Douglas Engelbart was stationed in the Philippines when he read Vannevar Bush's "As We May Think" in a Red Cross library. He became an early believer in Bush's idea of a machine that would aid human cognition. Later, he worked at Ames aeronautical lab, and developed the idea that would form the basis of today's computer interfaces. In the early 1960s, Engelbart began the Augmentation Research Center (ARC), a development environment at the Stanford Research Institute (SRI, Inc.). Here, he and his colleagues (William K. English and John F. Rulifson) created the oN-Line System (NLS), the world's first implementation of what was to be called hypertext. Yet this was only a small part of what ARC was about. As he states in "Working Together," Engelbart was particularity concerned with "asynchronous collaboration among teams distributed geographically" (245). This endeavour is part of the study of Computer Supported Co-operative Work (CSCW); software which supports this goal is often called groupware. "Augmentation not automation" was the slogan, the goal being the enhancement of human abilities through computer technology. The key tools that NLS provided were: outline editors for idea development; hypertext; linking; tele-conferencing; word processing; electronic mail; and user configurability and programmability. The development of these required the creation of: the mouse pointing device for on-screen selection; a one-hand chording device for keyboard entry; a full windowing software environment; on-line help systems; and the concept of consistency in user interfaces. Itemizing these accomplishments using today's terminology emphasizes their detachment from one another. However, NLS was an integrated environment for natural idea processing. The emphasis was on a visual environment--a revolutionary idea at a time when most people (even programmers) had no direct contact with a computer. Input was by punched cards and output by paper tape. Engelbart's work directly influenced the research at Xerox's PARC, which in turn was the inspiration for Apple Computers. Ted Nelson cites him as a major influence. In 1991, Engelbart and his colleagues were given the ACM Software System Award for their work on NLS.
Engelbart's patent for the mouse is only a representation of his pioneering working designing modern interactive computer environments. Engelbart was born and grew up near Portland, Oregon. He served in the Navy as an electronics technician during World War II, and received his B.S. from Oregon State University. After working for NASA's Ames Research Laboratory, he received a Ph.D. from the University of California at Berkeley. He then joined the Stanford Research Institute (SRI), earning a number of patents related to computer components. A main concern for Engelbert was how the computer could be used as a useful tool in tomorrow's office. While at SRI, he developed a hypermedia groupware system called NLS (oN-Line System). NLS utilized two-dimensional computerized text editing, and the mouse, used to position a pointer into text, was a critical component. During a 1968 demonstration, Engelbart first introduced NLS--this was the world debut of the mouse, hypermedia, and on-screen video teleconferencing. His project became the second host on Arpanet, predecessor of the Internet. In the 1970s and 1980s, Engelbart was a Senior Scientist at Tymshare, Inc., later acquired by McDonnell-Douglas. In 1989, he founded The Bootstrap Institute, which promotes the development of collective IQ through worldwide computer networks.
- Series 1. Accession 1986-030
  - Doug Engelbart talking about his papers and related anecdotes with Henry Lowood., 1986-030; 2 cassette tapes (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - “Games That Teach the Fundamentals of Computer Operation” by Douglas C. Engelbart, Member IRE., 1961, in IRE Transactions on Electronic Computers, p.31-41. footnote: Received by the PGEC, July 28, 1960 [folder labeled Patent Matters], 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No. 8, Oct-66; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No. 9, Nov-66; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No.10, Dec-66; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No.11, Jan-67; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No.12, Feb-67; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No.13, Mar-67; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No.14, Apr-67; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No.15, [May 1967]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No.16, [June 1967]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No.17, [July 1967]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Roman Monthly Letter Report No.18, Aug-67; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - SRI: Available Information On Subroutines, Nov-60; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 5890 Graphs Funds Spent, 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Draft - Final Report (5890), [July 1968]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Authorization (5890), [1966-1967]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pre-Proposals (ARP; 5890), [1966]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Memos and correspondence (5890), [1966-1968]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 5890-1 Networking (Reports on Meetings), [1967]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 5890- 1 Cost Sheets, [1966-1968]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 5890- 2 Cost Sheets, [1966-1968]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 5890- 999 Cost Sheets, [1966-1968]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - ARNAS "THINKPIECE - Possible Intellect-Augmentation Research", [11/11/1965]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ARNAS "THINKPIECE" - Expanded Facilities for Augmented Human Intellect Program, [6/30/1966]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 5890 ARNAS Authorisation & Contract, [1966-1968]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 5890 ARNAS Disc Pack Agreements, [1966-1967]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 5890 ARNAS Contractor Financial Management Report, [1966]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 5890 ARNAS Correspondence, [1965-1968]; 1986-030 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 5890-2 & 5890-999 Cost Sheets, [1966-1969]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 5890-1 ARNAS Cost Sheets, [1966-1969]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 5890 ARNAS Requisitions, [1966-1967]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 5890 Quarterly Technical Letter Reports, 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contents note
    [received empty]
  - ARNAS Quarterly Report No.1, [May 1966]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - ARNAS Quarterly Report No.2, Aug-66; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - ARNAS Quarterly Report No.3, Nov-66; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - ARNAS Quarterly Report No.4, [May 1967]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - ARNAS Quarterly Report No.5, May-Aug 1967; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - ARNAS Quarterly Report No.6, Aug-Nov 1967; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - SU Sem. -- Human Communication v. Computers, [1964]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, [1958-1959]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, [1959-1962]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Contact Report, [10/13/1961]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Electronics (Speech?), [3/14/1961]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - General Memorandums, [1960-1961]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Group-Work Seminars, [1960-1961]; 1986-030 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Statement on Outside Business Activities, [2/15/1962]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Office Plans, 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - MAG Program Scratch, [1958-1959]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Misc. MAG Scratch, 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lists of Publications on All-Magnetic Computer Techniques by Staff Members of the Stanford Research Institute, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - A Note on Internal Computer Communication, [10/17/1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Magnetic & Computer Projects, [May 1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lab Meetings on Project Management, [1960]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lab Planning, Engelbart's Notes, 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Lab Planning CTL, 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Computer Lab Memorandum, [13/7/1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Computer Lab; Plans for Program Development Funds for GSD, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Division Notices, 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Minutes of the Meetings of Subcommittee 4.10 (The Institute of Radio Engineers), [1960-1962]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - List of Unclassified Research Project Reports, [1959-1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - IRETEC Correspondence, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Spring Joint Computer Conference, [1962]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - System Engineeing Research, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Review Papers for IRETEC, [1962]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Western Electronic Show & Convention, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - American Federation of Information Processing Societies, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Paper on Social Implications (AFIPS), [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - IFIP Congress, 1962; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - PGEC Correspondence, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - PGEC, [1960-1962]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - PGEC, [1959]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Summary of Submitted Papers, 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Transactions, Review Notes (IRE), [1959]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - IRE Review Correspondence, [1960]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Stanford Research Institute [Maps and Papers], [1960]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Mottley's Seminars Planning, [April 1960]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Medical Plan, 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - SRI Data, [1958-1960]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Retirement Plan, [1958-1959]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Associates of SRI, [May 1961]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Computer Industry. Student Tour Information, [1957]; 1986-030 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    IRE Professional Group on Electronic Computers. Constitution and Bylaws
  - Professional Groups Manual, [April 1958]; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Institute of Radio Engineers (IRE). [Minutes, May 1960; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - IRE Professional Group Correspondence, Dec-58; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - IRE 4.10 Technical Discussion, May, Aug 1960; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Editorial Licence, [March 1960]; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - IRE San Francisco Minutes, [1959]; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Program on Human Effectiveness, 12-Dec-61; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Program on Human Effectiveness, Aug 24-25, 1961; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Automated Psycho-Motor Skill Training, 13-Dec-61; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Proposal for Participation in the Program on Human Effectiveness, 24-Aug-61; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Proposal for Participation in the Program on Human Effectiveness, Draft Copies; Aug 22, 1961; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Proposal for Participation in the Program on Human Effectiveness, Final Draft; Aug 25, 1961; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Augmented Human Intellect Program, [Draft; July 28, 1961]; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Technical Status Report for the Air Force Office of Aero Space Research, 28-Aug-61; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Current Grants for other Organizations, 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings on Computers, [1959-1960]; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Local Information Retrieval Group, Mar 7 1958; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Bibliographies on Information Retrieval, [1957-1959]; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Material on Filmsort, 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Material on LEFAX: Note Taking System, 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - McBee - Card File-Folder Templates, 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Material on Microfilm and CIM-card, 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Material on Microprint and Microfilm, [1955]; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Material for Microprint, [1953-1954]; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Material on Cormac Copying Machines, 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Material on Teletype Equipment, 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Lyle, David -- Information Storage and Retrieval System, [1958]; 1986-030 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Augmented Human Intellect Program, [March 1, 1962]; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - AHI Program, [1961-1962]; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Material on a Copy and Facsimile Machine, 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence American Documentation Institute Papers, [1960-1961]; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - American Documentation Institute; Registration List for 1960 Conference, 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Microelectronics, And The Art Of Similitude, [1959]; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Proposal for Research: Augmented Human Intellect Study, 8-Oct-62; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Memos to Participants in Augmented Human Seminar, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - A New Magnetic Logic System Using Simple Cores [Preprints, 16-Dec-58; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - List of Participants in Augmented Human Seminar, 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Seminar Minutes, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Materials on Artificial Intelligence Seminar, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Vote-Interrupt Equipment, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - A Project-promotion Possibility: Research on Information Storage and Retrieval, 6-Nov-59; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Augmented Man, And A Search For Perspective [Paper for WJCC, 16-Dec-60; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Memo: The Current Picture of Program Development for "Augmenting Human Intelligence"., [6/28/1961]; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Memo on Program at SRI on "Individual Information-Handling Problems, [1/21/1961]; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - A Conceptual Framework For The Problem of Augmenting Man's Intellect, 2-Oct-62; 1986-030 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Augmented Human Intellect Program, [March 1, 1962]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Augmented Human Intellect Study, [June 12, 1961]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - EU 60-251 AFOSR Augmented Human Intellect, [1960]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - SDS 940 Correspondence, [1967]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - SDS 940 - Internal Memos, [1967]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Air Force Office of Scientific Research (AFOSR) Advisory Committee, [1963]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with the Army Research Office, [1962-1964]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 940 Display Information, [1966]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - NAVCOSSACT Contact File, [1963]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bulletins of the Bay Area Systems Group, [1963-1965]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Material of the Association For Computing Machinery, [1961-1963]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Memo and Correspondence with the Rome Air Development Center, [1961-1964]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with the Air Force Office of Scientific Research, [1960-1963]; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with the US Atomic Energy Commission, 31-Oct-62; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence of W. K. English, Jul 1964-Dec 1966; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence of Douglas C. Engelbart, Jan 1962-Dec 1963; 1986-030 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: Donald I. Andrews, Oct 1966-Feb 1969; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: V.R. Baughman, Jan-Feb r 1969; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: Roberta A. Carillon, Jun 1968-Feb r 1969; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: David Casseres, Dec 1967-Feb r1969; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: Douglas C. Engelbart, Jun 1966-Feb r1969; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: William E. English, Jun 1966-Feb r1969; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - SRI Travel Expense Reports: Douglas C. Engelbart Official Correspondence, Jan-Dec 1967; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - SRI Weekly Time Reports: David E. Evans, Jun 1966-Feb 1969; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - SRI Weekly Time Reports: Ann Geoffrion, Oct-Dec 1968; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - SRI Weekly Time Reports: Martin Hardy, Jun 1966-Feb 1969; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - SRI Weekly Time Reports: Jon D. Hopper, Jun 1966-Feb r1969; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - SRI Weekly Time Report: Charles H. Irby, 1969 Feb; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - SRI Weekly Time Reports: Dean Meyer, Dec 1968-Feb r1969; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - SRI Weekly Time Reports: Stephen Paavola, Jun-Dec 1968; 1986-030 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: William H. Paxton, Jun 1968-Feb r1969; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: John F. Rulifson, Jun 1966-Feb 1969; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: E. K. Van De Riet, Jul 1968-Feb 1969; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: Margaret Ann Watson, Dec 1966-Dec 1967; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: Bary Pollack, Jul 1967-Sep 1967; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: Pat Conley, [June 1966 - June 1968]; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: R. Elton Hay, Jun 1966-Feb 1968; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - SRI Travel Expense Reports: R. Elton Hay, [1965 - 1968]; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Research Institute Weekly Time Reports: Stephen R. Levine, Sep 1966-Jan1968; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - SRI Travel Expense Reports: Stephen R. Levine, [1967-1968]; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - SRI Weekly Time Reports: Helen Price, [April - June 1969]; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - SRI Weekly Time Reports: Gerald L. Tisue, Jun 1968-Jan1969; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - SRI Weekly Time Reports: F.K. Tomlin, Mar-Aug 1969; 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Assorted Worker Files, 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Assorted Worker Files, 1986-030 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Douglas C. Engelbart: Shell Fellowship Lectures, [July 15-16, 1959]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Douglas C. Engelbart: Draft of Computer-Simulation Paper, 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Engelbart: Notes for the Computer-Simulation Paper, 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Engelbart: SRI Correspondencs, [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondece concerning: Engelbart, Games That Teach the Fundamentals of Computer Operations., [1961]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Notes for Computer Simultation Paper, 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - School Mathematics Study Group Monograph Project., [1960]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Douglas C. Engelbart: Games That Teach The Fundamentals of Computer Operations, 12-Jan-60; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Alan Bell: Digital Computer Demonstration - Summery of Principles, [March 1960]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Research Institute: Contact Reports, [1958-1960]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Engelbart: Rough Draft; Description of Magnetic Access Switches with Matrix Notation, [July 1960]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - MAD Seminars: Notes., 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Electronics Research Division; Seminar on Magnetics; Notes, [1958]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - MAD Notes, Drive, fi-fi plotter, [May 1958]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - MAD Notes; Bias, Range, Loss Analyses, 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - MAD Notes; Calculations, Possibilities, [1957]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Engelbart: Discussion od Solid-Magnetic-Register Possibilities, 30-Jan-59; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Articles and Papers on Magnetics, [1957-1959]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Articles and Papers on Magnetics, [1959-1960]; 1986-030 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - SRI Working Group on Science and Newly Developing Countries, [1960]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Engelbart: Notes on Report Production, [1960]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Jack C. Staller: Shrinking the Giant Brains for the Space Age, [June 1959]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Engelbart: A New Magnetic Logic System Using simple Cores, 1958 Dec; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence on: "A New Magnetic System"., 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence on "Similtude in Electronics"., [1960]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography of Publications and Unclassified Technical Reports by SRI-Members, [1960?]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Envelope with Notes & Bibliography
  - Engelbart; Document Requisitions, [1960]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Note-Card External-Index Forms, 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Article: Cyclops Cores Simplify, [1958]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence on Literature Requests, [1959]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Papers on Information Retrieval, [1959]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Literature Reference Notes, 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Frank Leary: Computers Today, [April 1961]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Proposal Forms, 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Engelbart: Research Proposal, Study of New Storage Media and Techniques, 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Misc. Gadget Ideas, 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Sequence Detector, 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Parametric devices, 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Papers by E. C. Crittenden, Jr.: A Computer Memory Element Employing Superconducting Persistent Currents, 1957 Oct; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    [Oct. 1957]
  - Correspondence and Notes concerning Aeronutronic System Inc., [1959]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Keyer, 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Shoulders, K.R. Electronic Micromachining Techniques, 1958 Oct; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Hesterman; Notes, [March 1959]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Kersh, Bert Y.: Correspondence and Notes, [1959]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Institute of Radio Engineers (IRE): Constitution and Personnel, [1957-1959]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Drawings of Basic Shift Register, 1986-030; [Films] (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Filmad Discussions. Notes for Project "High Speed Components (Computer), [1958]; 1986-030 (Box 10, Folder 28)